准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
痞老板学防身
编剧
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜总监
指导总监
动画总监
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
海之霸
好了  凯伦
All right, Karen
我要去购物了
I'm off to go shopping
什么鬼东西
What is that?
过来
Over here
所以说
So, uh
你有货吗
you got the goods?
那当然
Of course
我言必信行必果
I always deliver
很高兴能跟你做生意
Pleasure doing business with you
我也一样  见不得人的好朋友
Likewise, my shady friend
那下次同一时间
So same time next--
蟹堡王
我是来抢秘方的
I'm here for the formula
给我交出来  才不会有人
Hand it over, and nobody gets--
好像踩到什么恶心的东西上面了
I seem to have stepped in some revolting substance
没事
No matter
亲爱的  我回来了
Honey, I'm home
今天抢秘方一定很艰难吧
Tough day at work, dear?
没错
Yes
大家又踩到我了
Everybody stepped on me again
我知道
Well, I know
有什么能让我的小家伙振作起来
what'll cheer up my little man
一起借舞消愁
Let's dance those blues away
天啊
Oh, boy
舞厅
好耶
Oh, yeah
跳起来  谢尔顿
Go, Sheldon
你说得对  凯伦
You were right, Karen
我已经感觉好多了
I feel better already
我特想狂舞
I've got boogie fever
婚礼那晚后就再也没这么跳过舞了
We haven't danced like this since our wedding night
痞老板
Plankton?
不好了
Oh, no
不好意思
Pardon me
痞老板
Plankton?
痞老板  在吗甜心
Plankton, are you there, sweetie?
不好意思
Excuse me
痞老板
Plankton?
你在这啊
There you are
至少一小部分在这
At least part of you
我受够了
That's it
我再也不想任人践踏了
I'm not getting stepped on anymore
带我去实验室
Take me to my lab
好
Sure
不过还是先找你剩下的部分比较好
But let's find the rest of you first
脚部威慑装置1.1版本
Foot Deterrent, Version 1.1
开始测试
commence test
还不行
Not quite there
很多版本之后
脚部威慑装置  激光版
Foot Deterrent, laser thingy
应该能过了吧
Might as well get this over with
什么
What?
好
Yes
我天下无敌了
I'm invincible
好了  现在来做实地测试
All right, time for a field test
倒数三二一
in T-minus 3, 2, 1
我的脚
My foot
给我接招  高高在上臭火腿
Take that, you high-stepping ham
天啊
Oh, boy
来让那双大铁脚再也没法瞎踩了
Time to stop those big metal stompers
痞老板  你到底在干什么
Plankton, what in tarnation are you doing?
差点就把我爪子给烤了
You almost barbecued my dang paw
那就是重点
That was the point
不过  你刚刚那堆嗨呀的是怎么回事
But hey, what was that "hiyah" stuff you just did?
只是一点传统防身术罢了
Well, that was just good, old-fashioned self-defense
也就是  空手道
You know, karate
看样子你也很需要学防身
Looks like you could use a little self-defense too
要不然你就来我树屋吧
Why don't you swing by my dome
我来给你露两手
so I can show you some moves?
能让别人别踩我就行了
Anything to stop the stomping
痞老板  出来吧
All right, Plankton, come on out
我显得道袍好看多了
I make this gi look good
向你的师傅鞠躬
Now bow to your sensei
痞老板绝不向别人鞠躬
Plankton bows to no one
好
Good
现在可以开始了
Now we may begin
先来评估你当前的防身水平
We must first gauge your current level of self-defense
小心
Think fast
小心什么
Think what?
终于知道为什么这个叫运动鞋了
Now I know why they call it a sneaker
偷 袭
换个力度小一点的
Maybe something a little gentler
我不会跟你一样空翻
I can't flip like you
拖
只会砸锅
Only flop
鞋
好
OK
那就换这双
How 'bout these?
看来你缺乏基础
Seems like you lack the fundamentals
得给你做点基础训练
What you need is some basic training
好好好  长毛的小姐
Okey-dokey, furry lady
既然你已经掌握基础了
Now that you've mastered the basics
想必你已经准备好来真人快打了
I reckon you're ready to spar with a real partner
婴儿鞋
嗨  痞老板
Hi, Plankton
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob?
你别怕
Don't you worry
我会放水的
I'll go easy on ya
泡沫陪练靴
Foam sparring boots
我可不一定会手下留情
I can't promise I'll do the same
向对手鞠躬
Bow to your opponents
开打
Now fight
表现很好  痞老板
That was pretty good, Plankton
但别忘了时刻保持警惕
But remember to keep your guard up
没用的
It's no use
我太小了  很难不任人践踏
I'm just too small to avoid being stepped on
但是在空手道
But in karate
你最大的弱点也可能会是
your greatest weakness may also be
你最强的长处
your greatest strength
好
Yeah
但是在现实道  根本不可能有这回事
But in "rea-li-tay," that doesn't make any sense
由我来为你演示
Allow me to demonstrate
海绵宝宝  给我回旋踢
SpongeBob, give me the old roundhouse
可以借对手的冲击力
Your opponent's momentum can be used--
加以反击  无论你有多大
--against them, no matter your size
没事吧  海绵宝宝
You OK, SpongeBob?
我要能鞠躬的话  早就鞠了
I would bow to you If I could
不可思议
That was incredible
我来试试
Let me try
让技法浮现在脑海中
Visualize the technique
一抓一转  剩下的全部交给重力
Grab, twist, and let gravity do the rest
闭嘴
Shut up
你害我分心了
You're distracting me
成功了
I did it
当面打脸了  臭脚
In your face, feet
恭喜你  痞老板
Congratulations, Plankton
但要记住  这种技法
But remember, this technique
只能用来自卫  不能图谋不轨
is to be used strictly for self-defense
那当然  珊迪师傅
Of course, Sensei Sandy
眨眼
Wink
再也不见
Buh-bye
珊迪  你能送我去医院吗
Sandy, could you give me a ride to the hospital?
好啊  海绵宝宝
Sure, SpongeBob
好  谁想来打架
All right, who's looking to rumble?
你
You
这是什么无法解释的自然之力
What unexplained force of nature?
我感觉好强大
I feel so powerful
忍不住要使出这身力量干坏事了
And I can't help but use that power for evil
蟹堡王
老螃蟹
Oh, Krabsy
我回来了
I'm home
现在没人能阻止我了
No one can stop me now
秘密配方就要归我了
That secret formula will be mine
痞老板
Plankton?
怎么是痞老板
No, not Plankton
成功了
I made it
忍者保安
Security ninjas?
老螃蟹考虑得还真周到
Krabs thinks of everything
放马过来
Bring it on
敲敲门
Knock, knock
痞老板
Plankton
你是怎么绕过我的忍者保安的
How did you get past me security ninjas?
用空手道绕过的
With the art of karate
既然我现在会防身了
Now that I can defend myself
你的双脚要完蛋了
your feet are all doomed
等下你绝对笑不出来
You won't be laughing
我马上就要使出终极踩脚终结神功
once I use my ultimate foot-stomping finisher
跟你说个坏消息  痞老板
Bad news for you, Plankton
我没有脚
I don't have any feet
你什么
You what?
真是倒霉透了
Just my luck, I guess
任人践踏的失败滋味是不是很熟悉啊
The old familiar sting of "de-feet," aye?
医院
急诊
再过六到八个星期
Six to eight weeks
我就又能去蟹堡王发动进攻了
before I can attack the Krusty Krab again
好吧
Oh, well
起码我再也不用做牵引治疗了
At least I'm not in traction anymore
好耶
Oh, boy
只要再等六到八个星期
Only six to eight weeks
我就又能去蟹堡王上班了
before I can work at the Krusty Krab again
空手道真讨
Karate is a pain in the--
为泡芙健身
编剧
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
指导总监
动画总监
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
欢迎来到酷乐湖
不好意思  小姐
Excuse me, Miss
这位子占了吗
Is this seat taken?
现在就占了  水手
It is now, Sailor
三声铃声
Three bells?
午餐时间到了
It's lunchtime
最好弄点吃的来
Better get some food
卖奶酪火锅的
Oh, Fondue Man
小费才半毛钱
A 5 cent tip?
可真谢谢你了  先生
Thanks a lot, Mister
奶酪火锅
Fondue
最适合海滩约会的食物
The perfect food for a beach date
好
OK
不对
No
刚刚吃得真爽
Now, that was a meal
你说要不要
What do you say
下酷乐湖浪漫游个泳呢  我的甜心
to a romantic dip in the goo, my sweet?
我确实挺想洗掉身上沾到的奶酪
Well, I suppose I could wash off some of this cheese
尤金
Eugene
逆流卷走我了
The undertow's got me
救命
Help
救生员
激流里浮着个大屁股
Rump in a riptide
我来救你了  兄弟
I gotcha, bro
谢谢你  拉里
Thank you, Larry
谢谢
Thank you
尤金  不必多说
Eugene, don't try to talk
我先带你回家
I'd better take you home
再见  拉里
Bye, Larry
再次谢谢你了
Thanks again
拉里随时出马
Larry's always ready to step in
蟹堡王
跟你说吧  小子
I'm telling you, boy-o
那一吻  那一浪
that kiss, that wave--
我就快把我可爱的泡芙
I'm losing me sweet Puff
输给一个外壳发亮的小白脸了
to a shiny-shelled boy toy
可能是你看错了吧
Well, maybe your eyes were confused
不对
No
她就爱拉里的肌肉
She loved Larry's muscles
她都烦透了我这奶酪火锅老皮囊
She's sick of this old sack of fondue
听着  蟹老板
Look, Mr. K
泡芙老师肯定爱的是你的内在
I'm sure Mrs. Puff loves you for who you are
而不是你有多少肌肉
not how many muscles you have
看
Look
看好了  小子
Look, boy
衣服里面没晒黑  外壳软弱又无力
This farmer's tan, this flabby shell
要身材没身材
so undefined
蟹到中年老吃奶酪火锅  下场就这样
See the realities of middle age on an all-fondue diet
别看我
Look away
是个螃蟹都不应该这副德行
No crab should look like this
没别的选择了  小子
There's only one option, boy-o
一定得在下次约会前练好身材
I gotta get in shape before me next date
你也来帮忙
And you're gonna help
拉里健身房
那只壮龙虾肯定不认识我
That crustaceous hunk doesn't know who I am
也不知道我干嘛来  小子
or why I'm here, boy-o
加把劲
Go, go, go
好  好
Yeah, yeah
冲冲冲冲
Go, go, go, go
流汗
Sweat
我不该来的
This was a mistake
弃健身房逃命啊
Abandon gym
你能行的  蟹老板
You can do this, Mr. Krabs
全是为了泡芙老师
Do it for Mrs. Puff
你说得对
You're right
我要为泡芙健身
I'll do it for Puff
欢迎光临我的健身神殿
Welcome to my temple of the bods
少给我推销了
Save the sales pitch
我能行的
I got this
跟你说  那个其实是给
You know, that's actually for--
举重举完了
Finished me reps
好吧
OK
我可以教你怎么
I can show you how to--
好
OK
心率上来了
Got me heart rate up
蟹老板
Mr. Krabs?
没听过那谁
Never heard of him
第一天来一定不好意思了
Must be shy about his first day
如果你想健身  我很乐意帮你训练
If you want to work out, I'd be happy to help train you
好  多半确实得来点指导
Yeah, maybe I could use a few pointers
你先试试做点自由重量训练
Let's just try lifting some free weights
[ 自由重量：指可以举起并四处移动的
任何重量的器材，如哑铃 ]
拉里你看  我举起来了
Look, Larry, I'm doing it
海绵
Sponge--
不许偷自由重量器材  兄弟
No stealing the free weights, bro
不是说免费吗
Well, are they free or not?
自 由
从来没见过你这么不乐意健身的家伙
I've never met anyone as workout-averse as you
可我真不知道要怎么激励你
I just don't know how to motivate you
我知道怎么激励他
I know how to motivate him
钱  钱
Money, money
钱
Money
你这办法好  小兄弟
Nice trick, little dude
也没什么
That's nothing
我骗他吃药才叫好看呢
You should see how I get him to take his pills
好耶
Yeah
一周后
蒸汽浴室
健身健得真久啊
That was one heck of a workout
来看看连续健了168小时的身
Time to see what 168 straight hours of exercise
效果变得怎么样
does to the body
怎么回事  拉里
What's the deal, Larry?
我怎么没变壮
Why ain't I ripped?
健身得健一辈子  兄弟
Fitness is a lifelong journey, bro
只练一周没法改变体格
Can't change your physique in a week
桑拿房见  兄弟们
See you bros in the sauna
没法改变体格是吧
No one can change their physique, eh?
你好啊  女士
Hey there, ma'am
这片海滩占了吗
Is this beach taken?
天啊
Oh, my
尤金  你身材真好
Eugene, you're so well-defined
尤金
Eugene?
好
Yeah
看一看
Take a look
这就是长肌肉  各位
These are called gains, people
好
Yeah
肌肉真棒  蟹老板
Nice pecs, Mr. Krabs
我们爱你
We love you
全世界最壮的螃蟹
Strongest crab in the world
天不怕地不怕
I fear no man
老螃蟹
Krabs
拉里
Larry?
蟹老板
贻贝海滩
我要把你砸出我的壳  兄弟
I'm going to crack you right out of my shell, bro
蟹老板  真帅气
Mr. Krabs, looking good
那是拉里吗
Was that Larry?
他一定有好几分钟没健身了
He must have stopped working out for a few minutes
奶酪火锅
Fondue?
在海滩上
At the beach?
拉里有危险了
Larry's in trouble
来个谁快救救他
Someone save him
谁来给救生员救生啊
Who will lifeguard the lifeguards?
卖奶酪火锅的
Fondue Man
好
Yeah
行
OK
好耶
Oh, yeah
没错  我把场面救回来了
That's right, saving the day over here
你现在觉得我怎么样  阿芙
What do you think of me now, Puffykins?
你家老螃蟹可真是个英雄
Your old Krabsy is quite the hero
真是的
Puh-lease
我可不喜欢只顾自己的肌肉男
I'm not into muscle-bound, self-centered jerks
说什么
What's that?
我爱的男生就该稍微轻软一点
I like my boys a little soft around the edges
所以我跟拉里明天要来海滩约会
That's why Larry and I have a beach date tomorrow
拉里喜欢海滩约会
Larry loves beach dates
海滩约会
Beach date?
别走
Wait
我闹着玩的
I was kidding
我这身肌肉都是幌子
The muscles were just a ruse
泡芙
Puffy
你看
See
回来啊
Come back
阿芙  我可软了
Puffykins, I'm soft